Meier mss., 1927-2010
Indiana University Digital Library Program
- Recordings and multimedia, 1970-2008, undated (Box 17)
  - Programs on education, 1990-2005, undated
    - Episode 4: The Bottom Line (1980-Present), from School: The Story of American Public Education, 2001, Sept. 3-4, VHS, 57:21
      Includes a segment on Central Park East Secondary School and segments with Meier
    - Making the Grade, rough cut, ca. 2001, VHS, 62:00
      Program on testing and Central Park East I
    - Making the Grade, Part 2, from New York Voices, Thirteen WNET New York, 2005, DVD, 35:20 (Box 17)
      Program on small schools with host Rafael Pi Roman; includes a segment with Meier and a panel discussion with education reporters Joe Williams, David Herszenhorn, and Clara Hemphill
    - No Child Left Behind Report: Public Education in the Crosshairs, 2005, DVD, 76:36
      Includes segments titled McGuffey, Key Provisions, Rally, and Hamilton High School
    - DVD labeled Keynote with a Quicktime file containing segments of interviews with educators (including Meier) about the No Child Left Behind act, undated, DVD, Quicktime file 36:55
  - Student performances, 1970-2001, undated (Box 16)
    - Central Park East School I SING: Selections from the All-School Sing, Parents Association of the Central Park East School I School Music Program, 2001, Jan.-Feb., CD, 58:37
    - Video, 1997-2001, undated
      - CPE Opera: H.M.S. Pinafore by Gilbert and Sullivan, 1997, May 7-9, VHS, 38:34
        See also Inserts and booklets; H.M.S. Pinafore cast booklet
      - CPE Opera: No Laughing Matter by Seymour Barab, 1998, Mar. 30-Apr. 3, VHS, 33:40
        See also: Inserts and booklets; No Laughing Matter cast booklet
      - CPE Opera: A Very Special Gift by Seymour Barab, 2000, June 6-9, VHS, 41:08 (Box 17)
        See also: Inserts and booklets; A Very Special Gift cast booklet
      - Central Park East I: Spring Concert, 2001, May 24, VHS, 128:27
      - CPE Opera: The Dreameater by Gregg Smith and Kim Rich, 2001, May, VHS, 53:00
      - Little Red Riding Hood--CPE I Opera, undated, VHS, 45:30
  - Other, 1970-2007, undated
    - Tape labeled PS 144 school trip and ROG/Nick et al animations!, 1970s, VHS, 63:00
      Includes silent footage of children and adults (including Meier) on trips and in the classroom; silent, stop-action animations possibly by Meier's sons, Nick and Roger; silent home movies; and video of a woman singing
    - Memorial Service for Michael Harrington in Riverside Church, New York City, 1989, Sept. 15, VHS, 113:00
      Includes speeches by Dr. James A Forbes, Jr.; Stanley Sheinebaum; Luis Ayala; David Dinkins; Ruth Messinger; Jack Clark; Deborah Meier; Bogdan Denitch; Joseph Murphy; and Irving Howe, as well as a musical performance by Steve Chapin
    - Shanghai Racquet Club, Asia Pacific Real Estate, 2007, May 7and 13, CD, 94 photographs (Box 16)
      See also: World Conference on Transformation of Classroom Teaching in Shanghai, China
  - Inserts and booklets, 1993-2000
    - Note from Peter Hart to Meier with Effective School Restructuring: Putting Together the Pieces, 1993, Feb. 22
    - The Merrow Report: In Schools We Trust booklet, 1997, Jan. 15, (3 copies)
    - H.M.S. Pinafore cast booklet, 1997, May 7-9
    - No Laughing Matter cast booklet, 1998, Mar. 30-Apr. 3
    - A Very Special Gift cast booklet, 2000, June 6-9
- Additions, 1945-2010, undated (Box 18)
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1955-2006, undated (Box 18)
    Divided into personal and professional correspondence, with letters from Meier, to Meier, and between other parties.
    - Personal correspondence
      - Letters from Meier
        - 1955-1956
        - 1957
        - 1958
        - 1959
        - 1960
        - 1963
        - 1968
        - 1969
        - 1976
        - 1978
        - Undated
      - Letters to Meier
        - 1960s
        - 1970-1974
        - 1975-1976
        - 1977-1978
        - 1979
        - 1980-1984
        - 1985-1989
        - Undated, (3 folders)
    - Professional correspondence
      - Letters from Meier
        - 1960s
        - 1970s
        - 1980s
        - 2000s
        - Undated
      - Letters to Meier
        - 1960s
        - 1970-1974
        - 1975-1979
        - 1980-1981
        - 1982-1983
        - 1984-1985
        - 1986
        - 1987
        - 1988
        - 2000s
        - Undated
      - Letters between others
        - 1969-1978
        - 1980-1983
        - 1984
        - 2001-2005
        - Undated
  - Articles, 1968-2006, undated (Box 19)
    - Related to education, 1968-2006
    - Related to education, by Michael W. Apple, 1981-1982
    - By Deborah Meier, 1985-2004, undated
    - An Indian Education, by Lucianne Carmichael, 2000
    - Racing Through Childhood, Mission High School News, 1998-2000
  - Speeches, 1950-2010 (Box 19)
    - Speeches, with letters and papers, by Deborah Meier, ca. 1950-1970, undated
    - Drafts and notes of speeches by Deborah Meier, 2010, undated, (2 folders)
    - Political speeches including notes, by Deborah Meier, undated
    - Keeping Track, How Schools Structure Inequality, by Jeanne Oakes, 1985
    - Women Progressive Leaders in the Twentieth Century, by Susan Semel, 2004
  - Educational materials, 1970-2009 (Box 19)
    - Floor plans and notes of visits to London schools, 1970
    - Educational articles relating to school testing, 1973-1987, undated
    - Awards information, 1977-1988
    - Annual conference schedules, 1984-2006
    - Socialist forums, 1986, undated
    - Commencement and convocation information, 1987-2009
    - School planning and programs, 1999-2007
    - Lecture announcements, 2005-2009
  - Publications, 1945-2006 (Box 19)
    - New Party News, 1945-1946
    - Educational publications, 1978-2006
  - Newspaper clippings, 1983-2006, undated (Box 19)
    - 1983-2006, undated
  - Audio/Visual materials, 2009 (Box 19)
    - Photographs, Deborah Meier, York convocation, 2009
    - DVD, York convocation, DVD, 2009
  - Ephemera, 1988-1998, undated (Box 19)
    - 1988-1998, undated